this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC - Radio net SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
softball al zero is the easiest and
fastest way to implement authentication
and authorization architectures into
your apps and api's allow your users to
login with username and password social
and enterprise identity providers such
as Facebook Twitter ad or office 365
without passwords using slack or
whatsapp getting started is very easy
use one of more than 40 SDKs and add a
few lines of code no credit card
required get the free plan at auth0 dot
io / SC radio that's a uth the number 0
io / SE radio ozzie row is trusted by
developers at Atlassian Mozilla
Optimizely in financial times try it out
at our zero dot io / se radio and get
back time building core features
[Music]
for software engineering radio this is
Elena Salinas today I have with me
searching God ray searching God ray is
VP of Product Management at software AG
he is responsible for managing the
hybrid integration platform IOT micro
services and API management
prior to joining software AG searching
worked with Accenture where he worked on
making IT strategy engagements in the
high technology sector fire to Accenture
searching worked as a Solutions
Architect at BearingPoint searching
gather welcome to software engineering
radio thanks thanks for inviting me for
this chat regarding IOT yes today we
will be talking about the Internet of
Things and its architecture the Internet
of Things is also known as IOT and it
has enabled many new business models and
applications first to understand what
IOT is what are some of those new
applications and business models yes so
IOT stands for the Internet of Things
and it's really a concept about
connecting any device to the Internet
and to other connected devices so you
can think of IOT as a giant network of
connected things and people right and
what this is enabling businesses to do
is to create new business models as well
as within their existing businesses look
for newer optimizations or newer
efficiency improvements so for example
you could think of a product such as
factory machine or something you can
actually track the performance of the
product in real time and then can offer
additional benefits like predictive
maintenance services such that even
before the factory machine or the
product in question can actually break
down and cause a stoppage in in
production you can go and fix it so
there is a number of such applications
and we are also seeing new business
models
being generated so so like instead of
selling a particular machine you can
rent out a machine and then you can
charge based on the usage of the machine
and this is all possible because of IOT
you mentioned first IOT is about
connecting any device to the Internet
what are some examples of those devices
that you've seen that businesses are
connecting to the Internet
there is I'm actually the sky's the
limit because any device that can be
connected will be connected and you can
certainly build applications so in the
consumer world what we see is the nest
thermostat which is a connected
thermostat that allows you to monitor
your home monitor the temperature inside
of your home on the business-to-business
side we are working with customers in
which are providing connected car
solutions where they have built-in
sensors in the cars and they are
tracking the driving habits of cars we
are also having customers where they are
putting sensors within printers so that
they can track the performance of the
printer the toner quality and if there
is a mechanical breakdown then they can
detect that before the breakdown
actually occurs so those are some of the
examples one thing that you mentioned at
the beginning yes IOT is about
connecting any device to the Internet
what are some of the challenges of
connecting devices and creating IOT
applications you know there have been
many surveys that have been done on the
challenges of IOT adoption for example
the survey that comes to my mind was
done by The Economist magazine they have
a Economist Intelligence Unit which is a
subsidiary that provides advisory
services so earlier this year they
created they took a survey and they
found out that the top challenge for IOT
adoption was the high cost of investment
required in IOT infrastructure the
second challenge that they found was was
related to security and privacy concerns
now
these challenges you know they have been
there for a while and as far as the
expensiveness of IOT infrastructure is
concerned I firmly believe that or a
period of time the cost of deploying IOT
solutions will come down in fact Moore's
Law will will eventually kick in and
will bring down the cost of these IOT
devices as well as the sensors and chips
and finally I believe I truly believe
that the devices will become more
powerful and functional so right now
when you look at the IOT investment
model you need to really look at what
use cases you are going for and what are
the benefits and there are many use
cases that we find where the cost of
implementing the IOT solution is well
worth the cost because the benefits are
are even greater so that's where we are
just to confirm what you just said you
mentioned part of the cost is the
sensors themselves and the devices yeah
absolutely okay so what happens is that
or over last five to ten years we have
seen the rise of the smartphone as an
example a typical iPhone has seven or
eight sensors so what is happening is
that as new devices come in they have
built-in sensors in them and you can
take advantage of those sensors and
because of the widespread use of smart
phones the price of these sensors is
also coming down so yeah I mean a part
of the cost is in the sensors and the
chips but that is also coming down and
through the internet-of-things Network
which is these devices that are
connected to it they're exchanging data
what are the main industries that are
adopting the Internet of Things well
there is strong IOT adoption across all
industries but one industry that stands
out is the manufacturing industry in
fact this is an industry that I work
with a lot given that I work with
software AG which is based out of
Germany in fact in Germany there is a
term called as industry 4.0 which is
used to describe the fourth Industrial
Revolution so industry four dot is all
about
factories that use information and
communication technologies to digitize
their processes and then they can reap
huge benefits in the form of improved
quality or increased efficiency and
lower cost and all of this is being
possible through IOT so as an example
software AG has just formed a joint
venture called Atomos with four other
manufacturing partners and and this
joint venture is really about taking
software AG's cloud-based platform and
then allowing these four partners to
build IOT applications on that platform
for their customers in fact Adam o
stands for adaptive manufacturing open
solutions so we see manufacturing as a
key area but then you know there could
be applications of that in healthcare we
have seen retail being a big adopter of
IOT solutions so there is a lot of
industries that are coming over but
manufacturing is just the standout just
because of industry for oh and other
things and maybe also because of the
impact in manufacturing like lowering
costs and things like that
absolutely so lowering cost improved
efficiency things like you know
providing additional capabilities like
predictive maintenance because it's all
about you know trying to prevent the
breakdown of machines and trying to fix
the machine before the breakdown occurs
yeah exactly in the traditional way
would be there's a factory a machine
stops working then you call maintenance
they might even take the machine or come
to repair it there whereas with this
predictive way you will know oh this
machine might fail next week absolutely
so you plan ahead for that downtime
absolutely yeah that's that's exactly
what is happening with predictive
maintenance let's talk about the types
of objects more water for example good
candidates to be connected in IOT we
talked about factoring machines is there
anything else that you consider a good
candidate there are many examples of
connected devices or machines in both
the b2c and the b2b world I talk about
the nest thermos
there has been this iconic button that
came from Amazon that many brands are
now integrating with so you can have
that button which is actually kind of
sticks to your refrigerator and you can
just press it to order things like your
milk or your detergent and things like
that but across our customer base
software AG's customer base we are
seeing physical assets that includes you
know factory machines air compressors
printers being connected to power IOT
use cases you know those use cases as I
mentioned earlier could be predictive
maintenance track and trace and things
of that nature we are also having
examples of a connected car or even
windmills that are generating
electricity from wind they have sensors
in them to make sure that they are that
they are operating optimally and they
are generating optimal amount of
electricity so the choice of the object
is really dependent upon the use case
and we see wide adoption across a number
of these objects mm-hmm what about the
data that these devices are exchanging
in the Internet what's an example of the
data the data again depends upon the
device that is being tracked in real
time so I will give you an example of
octo telematics which is a customer of
ours now they have put sensors in over
15 million cars and those sensors are
sending data and essentially octo is
tracking the driving habits of these
drivers and they're collecting all the
data they are deriving insights in real
time as well as via batch analytics and
then they are making these insights
available to insurance companies so that
they can provide customized or
personalized quotes to these drivers
based on their driving habits we also
have another example of a printing
company that is tracking the status of
the printers they are tracking the
status of the print quality as well as
the toner levels and then you know using
that information to send maintenance
crews out to those customers where the
printers
are located so that they can fix the
printers before there is a mechanical
breakdown another interesting case that
we have is of an air compressor company
that actually changed their business
model so air compressors these are
devices that are used in constructing
large buildings as well as houses and
things like that and typically the
construction company would buy these air
compressors and that basically means
there is a huge upfront investment and
when you are not building anything those
compressors are are not used so the new
business model is to rent out these air
compressors and using sensors that are
built into the compressor they can keep
track of the amount of compressed air
used per day per hour and then this
company is able to charge their
customers on a usage based way as
opposed to just selling these machines
outright so again this is a new business
model for them which is again powered by
IOT so there is a you know a wide range
of data that can be tracked yes and some
of the ones you mentioned are the amount
of air being compressed in the case of
the printer the toner quality for the
nest thermostat I imagine is the
temperature at various times of the day
absolutely what about the format of this
Delita
is there a standard of how this data has
to be exchanged for example json xml or
something like this yeah so there are
multiple protocols for exchanging this
data and it really depends upon the
device that is basically sending this
data for example we have numerous
protocols like MQTT which is Message
Queuing telemetry transport this is a
lightweight pub/sub protocol for
bandwidth constrained networks we also
have a rest-based protocols we have for
certain devices we have OPC OPC UA which
is a standard to integrate with some of
the industrial equipment there are many
such protocols and as far as the data
formats that are concerned it could be a
JSON format which is typically used
because
again the size of the JSON payload is
smaller but in some cases we have seen
XML being exchanged as well and then
there are certain devices where there
are certain device specific data formats
that are being used again the whole idea
is that you want to send the information
without putting in a lot of padding in
that information to increase the size so
you want to send the information or a
bandwidth constraint network and the
whole idea is to make it as small as
possible so there are multiple exchange
formats what was the name of the first
one that you mentioned MQ t mq tt T as
in Tom T as in Tom okay
and it means message queue message
queuing telemetry transport which is
MQTT then there is a rest-based protocol
called CoAP and then there is OPC or OPC
UA these are all data protocol standards
earlier in the show you briefly
mentioned security and IOT I want to
talk about this a little bit more with
the Internet of Things where essentially
building a world size robot some people
say what are some of the potential
security threats that stand out
well as I mentioned in the economic
intelligence unit survey on the
technical side the topmost challenge was
security and privacy yeah most of the
IOT data originates from these connected
devices and sensors that are outside of
your network so the attack surface for
IOT is much higher than a traditional
software application that is installed
within your data center so security
plays a very important role in in an IOT
application and there are a lot of ways
by which an IOT application can be
hacked for example you need to ensure
that there is physical security right so
whether it is your connected devices or
sensors that are out in the field they
have proper security so that no one can
can access them using unauthorized
credentials then there is network
security the data that is being
transmitted back from these connected
devices to your I o T application it
needs to be sent in a manner that it is
secure so use using standards like
Secure Sockets Layer then there is
application security your application
that is receiving all this data and one
of the facets of of an IOT application
is that you will receive a large amount
of data because you have tens of
thousands of devices that you are
tracking and so as you start getting all
this data you have to make sure that
your application is robust enough and
because it is being exposed to the
Internet it can handle things like
injection attacks like sequel injection
or session stealing or even denial of
service attacks and then finally you
need good access control and
authentication not only at the device
level but also at the application level
so there are many many layers of
security that you need to worry about
and you need to make sure that you have
the right kind of defenses built into
each layer so that an IOT application
can can work without anyone causing any
any harm to it yes that's an interesting
way of putting it you mentioned there's
a
networks itself has to be secure there's
also the device and the application
that's in the IOT device right
absolutely the application is both at
the IOT end meaning near to the devices
because you can have you you can have a
device that is connecting to many of
these sensors but you can also have an
application at the main IOT hub that is
processing all that information and both
of these need to be protected and you
also mention part of the risks might be
not handling authentication correctly
yeah so so there was physical security
network security application security
and then the final one was just access
control so making sure that you have
proper authentication and authorization
for IOT application and you have fine
grain control or entitlements so that
different users get to do their jobs but
they are not a given full access into
the system okay cuz I one reminded me
yesterday
I think November 19 I saw Germany banned
smartwatches for kids because apparently
some people could listen through the
SmartWatch so I guess that might be
related to that access control right
would this be a good example to
illustrate access control well that
would be more of a you know how out of
the physical security of that watch as
well as the as the data that is now
being accessible so it is I would say it
is more around the physical security and
the network security rather than the
access control themselves
okay so access control might be then we
have the Machine from the factory
connected I should only have access to
certain actions of the machine or yeah
so the access control is more on the
application side okay so it is on the
IOT hub side okay so making sure that
the right people get access to the
functionality to control the devices as
a force - I see just giving super user
access to everyone yeah
because some of these can be fatal or
not so fatal the ones that I've read
about is somebody suddenly can decide to
turn off the elevators from buildings
and people end up being trapped there
yeah absolutely I'm going to talk yeah
there are numerous such such a ot
systems that have been hacked in the
past so for example in the recent past I
think in last year or so there was a
distributed denial-of-service attack
using IOT devices so in this case what
really happened was the devices that are
out in the field they were provisioned
with their default user ID and password
so someone who did the provisioning they
did not even bother to change the
default user ID and password so hackers
were able to because this devices are
accessible over the Internet hackers
were able to to ping that device and to
get into that device and install a
malware in this case this malware was
called Mirai and then this Mirai malware
what it did was it used all these
devices to create a distributed
denial-of-service attack that caused
large portions of the Internet to go
down like Netflix was down there was
twitter was also impacted so this was a
huge attack using IOT devices
unprotected IOT devices I see and again
in the security space are there some
minimum security standards that have to
be in place in an IOT system
yeah absolutely there are certain
minimum security standards that have to
be present for an IOT application in
fact this area has not really been a
focus area until recently when the US
government created what is now called as
the IOT cybersecurity Improvement Act of
2017 and this proposed bill would
require all devices to maintain certain
minimum security standards so that they
can even be purchased by federal
government for their IOT applications so
this is the first time that we are
seeing a government acting and creating
an act for some minimum security
standards and these minimum security
standards you know they they make a lot
of sense for example one of the goals of
this act is that you have to remove the
hard-coded passwords and for each device
you need to have a separate credentials
then you need to ensure that there is
SSL being used for communication between
devices and the IOT servers and then
there is also a provision to make sure
that the IOT devices themselves have
been are being patched on a regular
basis so that they they are secured
against different forms of malware and
then the other thing is to maintain an
accurate inventory of all the devices
and to ensure that they are not being
tampered so it makes a lot of sense and
it's good to see that there is now an
official access that is being discussed
and this proposed bill will make it
almost mandatory and I hope that this
will be followed across the industry not
just by the federal government I wanna
switch gears now and talk about another
area that you've worked on which is
cloud-based IOT can you explain what
cloud-based IOT means specifically that
we mean by the cloud is that a
cloud-based IOT platform is a set of
fully managed and integrated services
that allow a customer to easily and
securely connect manage and ingest IOT
data from all of
these connected devices now once the
data is is ingested the platform then
can provide additional services to
process this data to analyze and
visualize that data in real time and
finally one of the highlights of an IOT
platform is to not only analyze this
data but then also allow actions to be
taken based on the insights gained from
this data by implementing workflow based
apps or by integrating this data with
on-premises and cloud-based applications
so all of these capabilities when they
are present in the cloud are offered as
a fully managed and integrated services
that is what makes in a cloud-based IOT
platform and for example in inactions
one thing that I can think of is if you
have a room of servers and then you're
monitoring the temperature if that a/c
suddenly stops working take an immediate
action of turning off the machines right
yeah so for example in this case your
IOT application is in the cloud but
you're a CEO or is located in in at your
home and one of the challenge is that
the a/c is sending a continuous stream
of data to the cloud based IOT platform
but it is going over the Internet and as
long as the Internet is active you can
process the data and then you can turn
off the AC or you can turn on the AC but
what happens if the internet is down
then you need the ability your IOT
platform needs the ability to do some
local processing as well so it really
depends upon where where and how much
processing you want to do locally versus
in the cloud or you can even put the
critical functionality to also work
locally I guess absolutely yeah that is
the whole idea mm-hmm that's a great
point
don't let security checks be a burden on
your software deployment fair code
greenlight gives you secure coding
feedback in seconds directly in your IDE
try Verico hood greenlight for eclipse
free for 30 days and type in devera
codes binary static analysis engine
delivering in-depth and accurate results
to developers in just seconds request
your trial of greenlight for eclipse
today by visiting very code comm /
greenlight - trial not using eclipse
visit code comm slash greenlight for
information on Visual Studio and
IntelliJ plugins let's talk a little bit
about the enterprise one thing that I
saw is software AG works a lot with
enterprises so I'm wondering what are
the needs of an enterprise when they're
starting to build an IOT application ok
so an IOT application is quite complex
right it has multiple moving parts and
the key requirements for any IOT
application is device connectivity and
management for example any IOT
application is potentially going to
integrate thousands of devices with
different connectivity and management
requirements and then of course it has
to integrate with those different
devices or very proprietary protocols
and standards so that is something that
is truly very important once these
devices are connected and as the data
starts flowing then you need real-time
data processing because you need to make
sense out of that data that is coming at
you at a very fast pace and deliver
insights within a matter of minutes or
within a matter of seconds actually and
then finally you still need the ability
to take actions on that data so based on
the insights that you have gained you
can then integrate that data for example
let's say you are monitoring a factory
machine and you realize that there is a
problem with that machine and you need
to order a new part and then you also
need to send the technique
to fix that machine so what this means
is that you need to first integrate with
the ordering system which might be an sa
PE ordering system so you need that
integration capability once you have
ordered that part then you need to based
on the delivery of the part or the
shipment date associated with that part
then you need to schedule an appointment
in your service management system so
that you can actually have a physical
person go and fix the machine so there
needs to be a lot of integration and
finally you need to develop workflow
based apps so that if there is any
manual intervention that is required
then you can then you can recognize that
there are tasks the manual tasks that
need to be carried out and you can
assign it to the right person who can do
those tasks so there is a lot of moving
parts you need device connectivity
management you need enterprise and cloud
integration you need real-time data
processing and you need workflow
automation as well so are these the
components of an IOT platform in general
absolutely any IOT platform including
software AG's cumulus 'ti IOT platform
has these components what we are seeing
in the market is that there is no single
vendor that can provide all of these
components what we have tried to do with
cumulus 'ti IOT is we have bundled
together best-of-breed
capabilities in device connectivity and
management enterprise and cloud
integration API management real-time
streaming analytic capabilities as well
as workflow automation and then on top
of that we have put solution
accelerators and what I mean by solution
accelerators is that these are use cases
that we see very often being deployed by
our customers such as predictive
maintenance so we have gone above and
beyond and we have created prepackaged
templates so that when a customer is
implementing an IOT app they can just
use the predictive maintenance templates
and they can gain from our experience in
implementing such kind of applications
at other cost
and they can get a head start and
quickly build that application so it is
not just the product offerings but also
the templates and the industry
experience that is part of the IOT
platform mm-hmm so in this sigh o T
platform I you described you mentioned
there's a integration layer also the
workflow component is this platform
structure also the IOT architecture just
want to understand if I'm getting the
terms correctly so there's a IOT
platform components but we can also have
an IOT architecture or is it the same
thing yeah so most of the components of
that I mentioned earlier are part of the
IOT architecture now it really depends
upon you know you don't need all of
these components to kickstart or to
build your first IOT application I think
you will start with something like
device connectivity and management and
you need enterprise and cloud
integration those are the most important
components you can bring the other
components depending upon your
requirements so for example if you have
tens of thousands of devices and you are
getting a lot of data and you want to
quickly gain some insights into that
data so that let's say you are
monitoring a temperature of a nuclear
power plant or something like that and
if the temperature is increasing then
you want to shut down that plant and
this particular thing is so time
critical that you need to analyze the
data in real time and that's where ever
you need streaming analytics whereas in
some other cases you don't care about
taking decisions by the second and at
that time you can possibly take all of
that data and analyze it using a batch
analytics layer like a Hadoop so it
really depends upon your use cases but I
would say that certain components are we
almost see them all the time and then
certain other components you can bring
in as per your requirements okay let's
talk about this a little bit more so the
way that you mention is there's a data
source that consists of thousands
of devices and then you have a data
processing layer and there are two
options one that you mentioned is
streaming analytics or in batch can you
just describe in a little more detail
what streaming analytics means yes so
streaming analytics is the ability to
constantly do statistical analytics
while on a stream of data so this is
stuff that is happening in real time
right so you you have a live streaming
data and streaming analytics allows for
management monitoring and real-time
analytics of that live streaming data
versus batch analytics which is not
real-time in nature so in this case what
happens is you want to do let's say
historical analysis so you you want to
take the data from for the last one
month or the last one week or the last
one here and then you want to do number
crunching on that to figure out trends
across a large quantity of data hmm
whereas with streaming analytics you
want to calculate the trend within a
small slice of time typically less than
a second or something like that
and again you know there are use cases
where as I mentioned if you if there are
time critical use cases where you need
to get that insight at that moment and
then act on it then you would choose a
streaming analytics layer if you are
okay with doing historical or batch
analysis then you would just store all
of that data in a Hadoop and then kind
of do batch processing of that so it
really depends upon your use cases and
both of them actually we are seeing that
our customers are using both of them to
figure out insights because you get
different insights from streaming
analytics versus difference in insights
from batch analytics so for the batch
one going back to an earlier example I
can think of the one about predicting if
a machine or a factory will fail you
might want to look at how it's been
behaving for the past three months or
something like this right so in this
case I would say that you would need
streaming analytics so for example well
it will be a common
so what you can do is you can look at
the past three months of data and based
on that you can create a machine
learning algorithm and then apply that
machine learning algorithm in real time
in your streaming analytics layer
because you do want to know if the
machine is failing then you do want to
know as early as possible you don't want
to do this analysis after the fact and
then basically by that time the machine
has already failed because the value of
the IOT application is to prevent that
failure and to do predictive maintenance
before the machine fails I see and what
would be one where it can be purely
streaming analytics would this be more
for critical scenarios like maybe I
machine at a hospital or something like
this well absolutely anything that is
time constrained now again you know
streaming analytics is not as you know
silver or a golden bullet I mean it all
depends upon you know the amount of data
that you can process and the analytics
and the insights that you can get
depends upon how many events are being
pushed into the streaming analytics
layer so if your event is a very tiny
event then you can process tens of
millions of these events per second
whereas if you have large events and
then these large events invoke like
cement a scoring model or maybe you need
to update a database or you need to look
up a database or you need to apply some
business rules to identify trends or to
identify insights in this data then
obviously you are doing a lot of
processing within the streaming
analytics layer and therefore the
ability to process your events is
dramatically reduced so in this case you
might see that you you will be
processing thousand events or so per
second so it is not uncommon we see
within our customer base they are
processing multiple thousands to tens of
thousands of events per second but again
the ability to process this events
depends upon the size of the event and
the amount of processing the the rules
that you are applying within the
streaming analytics layer when I was
researching for
this interview I saw that you've worked
on building IOT applications
specifically also using micro services
and api's and you are presenting this
diagram where you talk about in addition
to the data sources layer and the data
processing layer that we've been talking
about there's this notion of an
enterprise integration layer can you
explain what this layer does
the enterprise integration layer is a
key requirement for any IOT application
and as I mentioned the example where
let's say you realize that a particular
asset like a printer or a factory
machine let's say it is having a problem
and you need to order a part or you need
to schedule a service technician to go
out and fix the machine
in this situation you need to connect to
back-end data sources like large
applications like si P Oracle and others
and in in some cases you might want to
integrate with cloud-based apps as well
so this is where the enterprise
integration layer you know fulfills this
key requirement so developers can write
services to extract data from the source
application and then Orkin can write
data to a target application like an S
ap ERP and while doing so the enterprise
integration layer provides capabilities
like transformations validation mapping
orchestration things of that nature so
an enterprise integration layer is key
for any IOT application and what is the
role of micro services in this layer
yeah so micro services is a new
architectural style for building the
next generation of web scale
applications so we have been building
applications for a long time now
and as far as the the standard for doing
integration architecture it used to be
some called as so ah which is
service-oriented architecture and this
is all about building large grained
services so that they can be reused
within your IT Enterprise portfolio so
so is all about reuse whereas micro
services which is I consider it as the
next step in the evolution of the so
architecture they're all about agility
and scalability so reuse is a secondary
concern in micro services whereas
agility and scalability are the top most
concerns
hmm so what we are seeing is that our
customers are adopting this new
architectural paradigm for building the
next set of web or IOT or mobile
applications and this
words not just microservices but it
includes other technologies like
containers api's DevOps events and these
technologies are interrelated with each
other so when you use micro services
typically use you need to use DevOps
because that's what gives you the
agility and then you need to use
containers and api's so all of these are
technologies are related to each other
and these are the I consider them as the
fundamental building blocks before the
next micro services style architecture
so you mentioned micro services are
about agility and scalability one thing
that I think of in micro services is
splitting the different areas for
example you can have a micro service
that deals with sign ups so if you have
a product that requires people to sign
up you have a service for that a micro
service and then you have other things
to look up pictures or things like that
and that's how we can scale quickly
because for example if your website
becomes very popular you are gonna have
to serve a lot more signups so you can
scale that micro service right that's
right something like this yep okay in
the concept of IOT what's an analogous
example like here I'm talking about sign
ups services but in IOT what is a
service what is it doing so at the end
an IOT application is made up of
services and it could be a service that
is analyzing the data that is coming
from the IOT devices so the whole idea
with micro services was that these are
smaller grained or micro services that
are independently deployable and
scalable so essentially what this is is
is that if you want to as you mentioned
scale a certain if you have certain
devices that are sending a lot of data
to a service then you can have multiple
copies of that service so that it can
scale to support the data load that is
coming from those
devices and this is actually coming from
this this style of architecture was
initially propeller eyes by companies
like Netflix and Amazon for example
there is as per the textbook definition
micro services are deployed
independently so that means there is a
lot more containers that will be running
because each micro service will be in
its own independent container and then
another facet of micro services is that
they don't communicate with each other
directly because that creates coupling
and that reduces the agility so the idea
is that the micro services will
communicate using a messaging layer and
then the final idea is that the micro
services will own their data so
essentially if a micro service is
working with a particular data then they
will have a data store that is allocated
to micro services now from a conceptual
standpoint this makes a lot of sense and
actually it makes a lot of sense to
develop some applications like the
Netflix application which is their main
customer service application it's also
their main revenue generating
application and so it makes sense to
develop a highly scalable application
using micro services technology but when
you then apply this concept to let's say
enterprise apps or even IOT apps that
are being developed you need to make
some changes to it because if you go
full-blown into micro services then you
would realize that you will have a lot
of moving parts and pieces and if you
have independent data stores then you
would have a data consistency problem
and of course if there is an error
within a micro service then how can you
debug that because that error could be
caused because there are errors in the
other micro services that are sending or
calling out this micro service so I
think adopting micro services blindly is
is something that I would caution
against what we are seeing our customers
are are adopting what I call as a mini
service architecture and this term is
became popular because Gartner started
using it but what we are seeing is that
a real-time use of microservices
architecture for IOT applications has to
be different than a traditional
microservices architecture and and
that's what we are seeing within our
customer base and this would just be
like a managing layer or something yeah
so what this means is that instead of
just blindly adopting microservices
architecture you could build mini
services which are slightly more
coarse-grained than than a micro service
and you can put these mini services
together in a single container as
opposed to deploying them in different
containers and that way you can reduce
your operating footprint and ultimate
the ultimate goal is to strike a fine
balance between agility scalability and
the need to manage a large number of
moving parts like containers so that's
what you need to use some common sense
and need to use a combination of both
micro service architecture as well as
mini service architecture to build your
application okay before we finish I want
to talk a little bit about machine
learning earlier in the show we talked
about predictive applications and you
mentioned you can use a machine learning
algorithm to help with this what would
you say the role of machine learning is
in an IOT application so there is a lot
of data that is flowing through because
of the nature of an IOT application and
you can apply simpler rules but then
machine learning provides the next set
of predictive rules that can be applied
and within the software a G's Q velocity
IOT platform we provide Zemin tests
which is our solution for hosting these
machine learning algorithms so
independent of how the machine learning
algorithm is built you can build it
using an R statistical language or you
can build it using Python it doesn't
matter how you build it but you
can actually plug that within the cement
engine and that way it becomes available
in our real-time data data processing
layer as well as within the batch
analytics layer so that it can be used
to provide predictive analytics on the
data that is flowing through the IOT
devices
well Sachin thank you for coming on the
show it's been very interesting learning
from you about building IOT applications
and its architecture yep thanks Adina
for inviting me and I enjoyed this
interview for software engineering radio
this is Elena Salinas
don't let security checks be a burden on
your software deployment fair code green
light gives you secure coding feedback
in seconds directly in your IDE try Vera
Code green light for eclipse free for
30-days and tap into Vera codes binary
static analysis engine delivering
in-depth and accurate results to
developers in just seconds request your
trial of green light for eclipse today
by visiting vera code comm slash green
light - trial not using eclipse visit
vera code comm slash green light for
information on Visual Studio and
IntelliJ plugins
thanks for listening to se Radio an
educational program brought to you by
Triple E software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at se - radio
net to provide feedback you can comment
on each episode on the website or reach
us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or
through our slack channel at SC
radio.com
you can also email us at team @ SC -
radio net this and all other episodes of
SU radio is licensed under Creative
Commons license 2.5 thanks for listening